

0

Zaragoza (Spain)



678-154-765



maserasen@gmail.com



sergio-asensio-in



sergio-asensio-cv

# Sergio Asensio

Mathematician and Software Analyst Developer with a solid background in web applications development and several programming areas such as: Full Stack Developer (FRONTEND, BACKEND), Web Designer, Web Services Implementation (REST/SOAP), Database Management...

During my 4 years of experience, I have attended multiple projects managed by different technologies such as Java, Angular, Salesforce and NodeJs, both alone as well as member of qualified teams helping me all of them in my professional growth and development.

Some of the most important tasks I have faced through my professional experience are: Improvement and optimization of projects architecture, analysis and implementation of the FRONTEND and BACKEND functionalities in the most simple and efficient way, define the database tables structure as well as the relation between them, establish the code architecture of main project modules in order to take them as referents to develop new ones, support and knowledge transfer to team's software developers, PR's reviews, etc.

I am a so persistent person with my objectives and this is precisely the aspect that I like most about my work, I see my day by day as challenges to defeat and the more innovative and challenging these are, the more motivated I feel.

## EDUCATION

2011 - 2016

Bachelor of Mathematics - Zaragoza University

LANGUAGES

Spanish English Mother tongue

Speaking and writting upper-intermediate level

SOFTWARE TOOLS

Java

Spring MVC – Spring Hibernate – Spring Boot – Maven – JSF –JPA – jQuery – AJAX – Javascript – Quarz – Apache Tomcat

Salesforce Angular Node Web Design  $Apex-Visual force-Heroku-Marketing\ Cloud-Schedule\ Jobs$ 

Typescript - Npm - Reactive Forms - NgRx - Presentational and Container Components - Smart Components

 $\label{local-equation} Express.js-Nodemon-Babel-Node-Knex.js-Objection.js-TypeORM$ 

HTML – JSP – JSPX – CSS – SCSS – Bootstrap 4 – Font Awesome 4– ChartJS

Web Services
BBDD
ETL
Code Editor
Task Management
Version Control

REST – SOAP

PostgreSQL – Oracle – SQL

Talend

Eclipse – Intellij – Visual Studio Code

Jira

Git – Github – Gitlab – Bitbucket – SVN – CVS

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# April 2020 - Present

# SOFTWARE FULL STACK SENIOR ANALYST ENGINEER - (UST Global)

Full stack senior analyst engineer in an Angular and Node hospital development app
through I was able to increase considerably the level of my Angular (NgRx framework),
Node (TypeORM framework) and Web Designer skills. Some of the most important tasks I
tackled with were: Estimation, development and demo's preparing of new modules
requested by the client, improvement and optimization of the project architecture both
BACKEND and FRONTEND, knowledge transfer and PR's review.

# May 2019 - April 2020

#### SOFTWARE FULL STACK ANALYST ENGINEER - (Grupo Oesia)

Full stack analyst engineer in a residue management project for Aragón government.My
main role was focused on the definition and implementation of the architecture and
functionalities of the FRONTEND (Angular 7) and BACKEND (Spring Boot -JPA)
modules of the project as well as the support and knowledge transfer to team's software
developers.

#### March 2018 - May 2019

#### SOFTWARE FULL STACK SENIOR ENGINEER - (Grupo Oesia)

- Technical analysis and development of several Angular (Angular 7) modules and Java REST services (Spring Boot -JPA) that were required within an environmental quality and waste management app.
- Main and only responsible of a final client proyect where I was in charge of the expansion of several functionalities related to Zaragoza's civil service app (PrimeFaces – JSPX - SQL).

#### February 2017-March 2018

#### SOFTWARE FULL STACK ENGINEER - (DxD Applications & IT Solutions)

- Structuring and code management of different Salesforce projects, mainly triggers, visualforces, workflows, REST service integrations and test classes.
- Diving, integration and publishment in Heroku of a Java SMSes data sending app integrated with NodeJs, Marketing cloud, SFDC and Talend platforms by REST services.
- Main responsible of the development and publishment in Heroku of a NodeJs Web service
  app which purpose was the massive user data sending to a SMSes sending data Company as
  well as the storage of the responses received in PostgresSQL.

	Maintenance and creation of new Angular modules for a car's concessionaire app.
March 2016 – February 2017	SOFTWARE FULL STACK JUNIOR ENGINEER - (DxD Applications & IT Solutions)
	<ul> <li>Assistance to software courses related to the competences: SAP (ABAP modality), Java and Salesforce.</li> <li>Participation in several maintenance Salesforce projects where I grew up as code developer and platform admin.</li> <li>Full stack developer in an energy market project to simulate some Salesforce functionalities through a Java Web application. Thanks to this project, I learnt and explored several set of tools such as: Spring MVC, Spring Hibernate, HTML,CSS,jQuery, JSP, Javascript, SQL, REST, AJAX, the study of the Heroku platform and its synchronization with Salesforce and the use of Talend tool for massive data migration (ETL).</li> <li>More information in: <a href="https://sergio-asensio-cv.berokuapp.com">https://sergio-asensio-cv.berokuapp.com</a></li> </ul>
COURSES	
March – 2016 April – 2016 April – 2018	SAP Formation Course, AVAP modality Java Formation Course Salesforce Formation Course Angular 6 Formation Course
PRESENTATIONS	
October – 2016 October – 2017	Salesforce Course Intructor Java Course Intructor
CERTIFICATIONS	
PUBLICATIONS	Java Standard Edition 6 Programmer Certified Professional (Score: 93%)
	Ecuaciones Diferenciales Implícitas y Clasificación de sus Singularidades. (URL: <a href="https://zaguan.unizar.es/record/36919/files/TAZ-TFG-2015-4450.pdf">https://zaguan.unizar.es/record/36919/files/TAZ-TFG-2015-4450.pdf</a> )